productsup.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy - Productsup

We welcome you on our web pages and appreciate your interest. This Website collects some Personal Data from its Users. The protection of your personal data is very important to us. Therefore, we conduct our activities in accordance with applicable personal data protection and data security legislation. We would like to inform you below which data of your visit is used and for which purpose.

#### Owner & Data Controller

 **Owner  
**Products Up GmbH  
HEAD OFFICE  
Bahnhofstr. 5  
91245 Simmelsdorf  
Germany

Phone: +49 (0) 30 60 98 5355  
Fax: +49 (0) 9155 263 999 3  
Email: [cloudinfo@productsup.io](mailto:cloudinfo@productsup.io)

Managing Directors: Kai Seefeldt, Johannis Hatt

Registration court: Nürnberg  
Commercial registry number: HRB 27214  
VAT no.: DE27057843

Should there be any further questions concerning the handling of your personal data, you are welcome to contact our data protection supervisor:

 **Data Controller**

Nils Möllers  
Keyed GmbH  
Siemensstraße 12  
48341 Altenberge

02505-639797

#### Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that this Website collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies, Usage Data, first name, last name, company name, address, country, email address, ZIP/Postal code, city, website and phone number.

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.  
The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using this Website.  
All Data requested by this Website is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for this Website to provide its services. In cases where this Website specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without any consequences on the availability or the functioning of the service.  
Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.  
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this Website or by the owners of third-party services used by this Website serves the purpose of providing the service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy, if available.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through this Website and confirm that they have the third party’s consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

#### Mode and place of processing the Data

 **Methods of processing**  
The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

 **Place**  
The Data is processed at the Owner’s operating offices in Germany and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller.

 **Retention time**  
The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data.

#### The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Analytics, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Contacting the User, Heat mapping and session recording, Tag Management, User database management, Managing contacts and sending messages and Remarketing and behavioral targeting.

Personal Data collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

 **Infrastructure monitoring  
**

This type of service allows this Website to monitor the use and behavior of its components so its performance, operation, maintenance and troubleshooting can be improved.  
Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and mode of implementation of these services, whose function is to filter the activities of this Website.

 _Pingdom (Pingdom AB)_  
Pingdom is a monitoring service provided by Pingdom AB.  
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: Sweden – [Privacy Policy.](https://www.pingdom.com/legal/privacy-policy/)

 **Advertising**

This type of service allows User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on this Website, possibly based on User interests. This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below.  
Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside this Website. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.  
In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service’s use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/)

 _Facebook Audience Network (Facebook, Inc.)_  
Facebook Audience Network is an advertising service provided by Facebook, Inc. In order to understand Facebook’s use of Data, consult [Facebook’s data policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/). This Website may use identifiers for mobile devices (including Android Advertising ID or Advertising Identifier for iOS, respectively) and technologies similar to cookies to run the Facebook Audience Network service. One of the ways Audience Network shows ads is by using the User’s ad preferences. The User can control this in the [Facebook ad settings](https://www.facebook.com/ads/settings). Users may opt-out of certain Audience Network targeting through applicable device settings, such as the device advertising settings for mobile phones or by following the instructions in other Audience Network related sections of this privacy policy, if available.

 _App Nexus_

Productsup uses third-party advertising service, AppNexus Inc., 28 West 23rd Street, 4th Floor, New York, NY 10010, USA, https://www.appnexus.com (“AppNexus”). For this purpose, we have implemented the AppNexus tracking pixel on our website (i.e., a code snippet). With the help of the tracking pixel, actions of our website visitors can be tracked. A personal reference is not being documented. Only statistical information is collected and transmitted to AppNexus. The aim is to optimize advertising campaigns and to broadcast interest-based advertising to our website users. If you do not want this, you can disable AppNexus tracking by pressing the opt-out button at: https://www.appnexus.com/en/company/platform-privacy-policy#choices. For more information on privacy at AppNexus, please visit: https://www.appnexus.com/en/company/platform-privacy-policy

Personal Data collected: Cookies, unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example) and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads). Privacy Shield participant.

 **Analytics  
**

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

 _Google Analytics (Google LLC)_  
Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google LLC (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Website, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

 _Hotjar Form Analysis & Conversion Funnels (Hotjar Ltd.)_  
Hotjar is an analytics service provided by Hotjar Ltd.  
Hotjar honors generic Do Not Track headers. This means your browser can tell its script not to collect any of your data. This is a setting that is available in all major browsers. Find Hotjar’s [opt-out information here](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out).

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: Malta – [Privacy Policy](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy) –[ Opt Out](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out)

 _HubSpot Analytics (HubSpot, Inc.)_  
HubSpot Analytics is an analytics service provided by HubSpot, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy) – [Opt Out](mailto:privacy@hubspot.com)

 _Google AdWords conversion tracking (Google LLC)_  
Google AdWords conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Google LLC that connects data from the Google AdWords advertising network with actions performed on this Website.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant.

 **Displaying content from external platforms  
**  
This type of service allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Website and interact with them.  
This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

 _Vimeo video (Vimeo, LLC)_  
Vimeo is a video content visualization service provided by Vimeo, LLC that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy.](https://vimeo.com/privacy)

 _YouTube video widget (Google LLC)_  
YouTube is a video content visualization service provided by Google LLC that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant.

 _Instagram widget (Instagram, Inc.)_  
Instagram is an image visualization service provided by Instagram, Inc. that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/)

 **Heat mapping and session recording**

Heat Mapping services are used to display the areas of a page where Users most frequently move the mouse or click. This shows where the points of interest are. These services make it possible to monitor and analyze web traffic and keep track of User behavior.  
Some of these services may record sessions and make them available for later visual playback.

 _Hotjar Heat Maps & Recordings (Hotjar Ltd.)_  
Hotjar is a session recording and heat mapping service provided by Hotjar Ltd.  
Hotjar honors generic „Do Not Track” headers. This means the browser can tell its script not to collect any of the User’s data. This is a setting that is available in all major browsers. Find Hotjar’s [opt-out information here](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out).

Personal Data collected: Cookies, Usage Data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.  
Place of processing: Malta – [Privacy Policy](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out)

 **Managing contacts and sending messages**

This type of service makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User.  
These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.

 _HubSpot Email (HubSpot, Inc.)_  
HubSpot Email is an email address management and message sending service provided by HubSpot, Inc.

Personal Data collected: email address and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy)

 **Tag Management**

This type of service helps the Owner to manage the tags or scripts needed on this Website in a centralized fashion.  
This results in the Users’ Data flowing through these services, potentially resulting in the retention of this Data.

 _Google Tag Manager (Google LLC)_  
Google Tag Manager is a tag management service provided by Google LLC.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)

 **Contacting the User**

 _Contact form (this Website)_  
By filling in the contact form with their Data, the User authorizes this Website to use these details to reply to requests for information, quotes or any other kind of request as indicated by the form’s header.

Personal Data collected: address, city, company name, country, email address, first name, last name, website and ZIP/Postal code.

 _Mailing list or newsletter (this Website)_  
By registering on the mailing list or for the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning this Website. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to this Website or after making a purchase.  
For an effective registration we need a valid e-mail address. In order to verify that an application is actually made by the owner of an e-mail address, we use the “double opt-in” procedure. For this we log the order of the newsletter, the sending of a confirmation mail and the receipt of the requested answer. No further data will be collected. The data is used exclusively for the newsletter and is not passed on to third parties.  
Personal Data collected: company name, country, email address, first name, last name and website.

You can revoke your consent to the storage of your personal data and your use for the newsletter at any time. In each newsletter you will find a corresponding link.

 **Interaction with external social networks and platforms**

This type of service allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Website.  
The interaction and information obtained through this Website are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.  
This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

 _Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (Twitter, Inc.)_  
The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy)

 _LinkedIn button and social widgets (LinkedIn Corporation)_  
The LinkedIn button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the LinkedIn social network provided by LinkedIn Corporation.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)

 _Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook, Inc.)_  
The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation)

 _YouTube button and social widgets (Google LLC)_  
The YouTube button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the YouTube social network provided by Google LLC.

Personal Data collected: Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy.](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) Privacy Shield participant.

 **Remarketing and behavioral targeting**

This type of service allows this Website and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of this Website by the User.  
This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.  
In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service’s use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/)

 _AdRoll (Semantic Sugar, Inc.)_  
AdRoll is an advertising service provided by Semantic Sugar, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.adroll.com/about/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://info.evidon.com/pub_info/573?v=1&nt=1&nw=false)

 _AdWords Remarketing (Google LLC)_  
AdWords Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google LLC that connects the activity of this Website with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout)

 _Facebook Remarketing (Facebook, Inc.)_  
Facebook Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Facebook, Inc. that connects the activity of this Website with the Facebook advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/)

 _Remarketing through Google Analytics for Display Advertising (Google LLC)_  
Google Analytics for Display Advertising is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google LLC that connects the tracking activity performed by Google Analytics and its Cookies with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout)

 _LinkedIn Website Retargeting (LinkedIn Corporation)_  
LinkedIn Website Retargeting is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by LinkedIn Corporation that connects the activity of this Website with the LinkedIn advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy) – [Opt Out](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie_policy)

 _Facebook Custom Audience (Facebook, Inc.)_  
Facebook Custom Audience is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Facebook, Inc. that connects the activity of this Website with the Facebook advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and email address.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/). Privacy Shield participant.

 **User database management**

This type of service allows the Owner to build user profiles by starting from an email address, a personal name, or other information that the User provides to this Website, as well as to track User activities through analytics features. This Personal Data may also be matched with publicly available information about the User (such as social networks’ profiles) and used to build private profiles that the Owner can display and use for improving this Website.  
Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails based on specific actions performed on this Website.

 _HubSpot CRM (HubSpot, Inc.)_  
HubSpot CRM is a User database management service provided by HubSpot, Inc.

Personal Data collected: email address, phone number and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.hubspot.com/legal/privacy-policy)

 _HubSpot Lead Management (HubSpot, Inc.)_  
HubSpot Lead Management is a User database management service provided by HubSpot, Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.hubspot.com/legal/privacy-policy)

 **Managing landing and invitation pages**

This type of service helps with building and managing landing and invitation pages, i.e., pages for presenting a product or service, where you may add your contact information such as an email address. Managing these pages means that these services will handle the Personal Data collected through the pages, including Usage Data.

 _Unbounce (Unbounce Marketing Solutions Inc.)_  
Unbounce is a landing page management service provided by Unbounce Marketing Solutions Inc., that allows this Website to collect the email addresses of Users interested in its service.  
Unbounce allows the Owner to track and analyze the User response concerning web traffic or behavior regarding changes to the structure, text or any other component of the created landing pages.

Personal Data collected: Cookies, email address and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: Canada – [Privacy Policy](http://unbounce.com/privacy/).

#### Additional information about Data collection and processing

 **Legal action**  
The User’s Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Website or the related services. The User declares to be aware that the Data Controller may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

 **Additional information about User’s Personal Data**  
In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Website may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

 **System logs and maintenance**  
For operation and maintenance purposes, this Website and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with this Website (System logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address).

 **Information not contained in this policy**  
More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

 **The rights of Users**  
Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above.

This Website does not support “Do Not Track” requests.  
To determine whether any of the third-party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.

If your personal data has been processed, you are affected by means of the GDPR and you have the following rights to the responsible entity:

 _1 Right of access  
_You may ask the person in charge to confirm if personal data concerning you is processed by them.

If such processing is available, you can request information from the person responsible about the following information:

  * a) the purposes for which the personal data are processed;
  * b) the categories of personal data that are processed;
  * c) the recipients or the categories of recipients to whom the personal data relating to you have been disclosed or are still being disclosed;
  * d) the planned duration of the storage of your personal data or, if specific information is not available, criteria for determining the duration of storage;
  * e) the existence of a right to rectification or deletion of personal data concerning you, a right to restriction of processing by the controller or a right to object to such processing;
  * f) the existence of a right of appeal to a supervisory authority;
  * g) all available information about the source of the data if the personal data are not collected from the data subject;
  * h) the existence of automated decision-making including profiling under article 22 (1) and (4) GDPR and – at least in these cases – meaningful information about the logic involved and the scope and intended impact of such processing on the data subject.

You have the right to request information about whether the personal data relating to you is transferred to a third country or to an international organization. In this connection, you can request the appropriate guarantees in accordance with art. 46 GDPR in connection with the transmission of information.

 _2 Right to rectification  
_You have a right to rectification and/or completion to the controller, if the processed personal data concerning you is incorrect or incomplete. The responsible person must make the correction without delay.

 _3 Right to restriction of processing_  
You may request the restriction of the processing of your personal data under the following conditions:

  * a) if you contest the accuracy of your personal information for a period of time that enables the controller to verify the accuracy of your personal information;
  * b) the processing is unlawful and you refuse to delete the personal data and instead request the restriction of the use of the personal data;
  * c) the controller no longer requires personal data for the purposes of processing, but you need them to assert, exercise or defend legal claims, or
  * d) if you objected to the processing pursuant to art. 21 (1) GDPR and have not yet determined whether the legitimate reasons of the person responsible outweighed your reasons.

 _4 Right to cancellation  
_4.1 You may require the controller to delete your personal information without delay, and the controller shall promptly delete that information if any of the following is true:

  * a) Your personal data is no longer necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or otherwise processed.
  * b) You revoke your consent to the processing pursuant to art. 6 para. 1 lit. a or Art. 9 para. 2 lit. a GDPR and there is no other legal basis for processing.
  * c) Pursuant to art. 21 para. 1 GDPR you give objection to the processing and there are no prior justifiable reasons for the processing, or pursuant to art. 21 (2) GDPR you give objection to the processing.
  * d) Your personal data has been processed unlawfully.
  * e) The deletion of personal data concerning you is required to fulfill a legal obligation under Union law or the law of the member States to which the controller is subject.
  * f) The personal data concerning you was collected in relation to information society services offered pursuant to art. 8 para. 1 GDPR.

4.2 If the person in charge has made the personal data concerning you public and pursuant to article 17 (1) of the GDPR is required to delete it, is taking due account of the technology available and the costs of implementation, including appropriate technical measures, to inform data controllers who process the personal data that you have requested the deletion of any links to such personal data or copies or replications of such personal data.

4.3 The right to deletion does not exist if the processing is necessary

  * a) to exercise the right to freedom of expression and information;
  * b) to fulfill a legal obligation required by the law of the Union or of the member States to which the controller is subject, or to perform a task of public interest or in the exercise of official authority conferred on the controller;
  * c) for reasons of public interest in the field of public health pursuant to art. 9 (2) lit. h and i and art. 9 (3) GDPR;
  * d) for archival purposes of public interest, scientific or historical research purposes or for statistical purposes pursuant to article 89 (1) of the GDPR, in so far as the law referred to in paragraph 1 is likely to render impossible or seriously affect the achievement of the objectives of that processing, or
  * e) to assert, exercise or defend legal claims.

 _5 Right to information  
_If you have the right of rectification, erasure or restriction of processing to the controller, he/she is obliged to notify all recipients to whom your personal data has been disclosed of this correction or deletion of the data or restriction of processing, unless: this proves to be impossible or involves a disproportionate effort.

You have a right to the person responsible to be informed about these recipients.

 _6 Right to Data Portability  
_You have the right to receive the personal information that you provide to the controller in a structured, common and machine-readable format. You also have the right to transfer this data to another person without hindrance by the person responsible for providing the personal data, provided that

  * a) the processing on a consent acc. art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR or art. 9 para. 2 lit. a GDPR or on a contract acc. art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR is based and
  * b) the processing is done by automated means.

In exercising this right, you also have the right to obtain the personal data concerning you directly from one person responsible to another person responsible, as far as technically feasible. Freedoms and rights of other persons may not be affected.

The right to data portability does not apply to the processing of personal data necessary for the performance of a task in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority delegated to the controller.

 _7 Right to object  
_You have the right at any time, for reasons that arise from your particular situation, to object against the processing of your personal data, which pursuant to art. 6 para. 1 lit. e or f GDPR takes place; this also applies to profiling based on these provisions.

The controller will no longer process the personal data concerning you unless he can demonstrate compelling legitimate reasons for processing that outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is intended to assert, exercise or defend legal claims.

If the personal data relating to you is processed for direct marketing purposes, you have the right to object at any time to the processing of your personal data for the purpose of such advertising; this also applies to profiling insofar as it is associated with such direct advertising.

If you object to processing for direct marketing purposes, your personal data will no longer be processed for these purposes.

Regardless of directive 2002/58/EC, you have the option, in the context of the use of information society services, of exercising your right to object through automated procedures that use technical specifications.

 _8 Right to revoke the data protection consent declaration  
_You have the right to revoke your data protection consent declaration at any time. The revocation of consent does not affect the legality of the processing carried out on the basis of the consent until the revocation.

 _9 Automated decision on a case-by-case basis, including profiling  
_You have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which has a legal effect on you or, in a similar manner, significantly affects it. This does not apply if the decision

  * a) is required for the conclusion or performance of a contract between you and the controller,
  * b) is permissible on the basis of Union or member State legislation to which the controller is subject, and that legislation contains appropriate measures to safeguard your rights and freedoms and your legitimate interests, or
  * c) with your express consent.

However, these decisions must not be based on special categories of personal data pursuant to art. 9 (1) GDPR, unless art. 9 (2) lit. a or g and reasonable procedures have been taken to protect the rights and freedoms and your legitimate interests.

Regarding the cases mentioned in a. and c., the person responsible shall take reasonable steps to safeguard the rights and freedoms and your legitimate interests, including at least the right to obtain the intervention of a person by the controller, to express his or her own position and to contest the decision.

 _10 Right to complain to a supervisory authority  
_Without prejudice to any other administrative or judicial remedy, you have the right to complain to a supervising authority, in particular in the member State of its place of residence, employment or the place of the alleged infringement, if you believe that the processing of your personal data violates against GDPR.

The supervising authority to which the complaint has been submitted shall inform the complainant of the status and results of the complaint, including the possibility of a judicial remedy under article 78 of the GDPR.

 **Changes to this privacy policy**  
The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Website and can request that the Data Controller remove the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users.

 **Information about this privacy policy**  
The Data Controller is responsible for this privacy policy, prepared starting from the modules provided by iubenda and hosted on iubenda’s servers.

#### Definitions and legal references

 **Personal Data (or Data)**  
Any information regarding a natural person, a legal person, an institution or an association, which is, or can be, identified, even indirectly, by reference to any other information, including a personal identification number.

 **Usage Data**  
Information collected automatically from this Website (or third-party services employed in this Website), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use this Website, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server’s answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User’s IT environment.

 **User**  
The individual using this Website, which must coincide with or be authorized by the Data Subject, to whom the Personal Data refers.

 **Data Subject**  
The legal or natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

 **Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)**  
The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization authorized by the Data Controller to process the Personal Data in compliance with this privacy policy.

 **Data Controller (or Owner)**  
The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization with the right, also jointly with another Data Controller, to make decisions regarding the purposes, and the methods of processing of Personal Data and the means used, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Website. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of this Website.

 **This Website**  
The hardware or software tool by which the Personal Data of the User is collected.

 **Cookies**  
Small piece of data stored in the User’s device.

 **More on Facebook**

Fan page operators and Facebook Ireland are joint controllers according to article 26 GDPR, we therefore like to inform you in the following about this constellation and the related data processing.

 ** _Joint controllers according to article 26 GDPR_**

Facebook Ireland Ltd.

4 Grand Canal Square

Grand Canal Harbour

Dublin 2 Ireland

and

Products Up GmbH

Bahnhofstr. 5

91245 Simmelsdorf

Germany

 ** _Data protection officer:_**

Keyed GmbH

Nils Möllers

 ** _Insight Pages:_**

Insight Pages can be based on personal data, which are captured in relation with a visit or interaction of a person on or with a page and its content.

 ** _Legal basis for the processing of personal data_**

Insofar as we seek the consent of the person concerned for the processings of personal data, art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR serves as the legal basis for the processing of personal data.

While processing personal data, necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party serves art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR as legal basis. This also applies to the processing necessary for the implementation of precontractual measures.

Insofar as a processing of personal data for the compliance with a legal obligations required, which is subject to our company, art. 6 para. 1 lit. c GDPR serves as legal basis.

If vital interests of the person concerned or another natural person require a processing of personal data, art. 6 para. 1 lit. d GDPR serves as legal basis.

If the processing for protection of a legitimate interest of our company or of a third party is necessary and the interests, fundamental rights and freedoms of the person concerned do not outweigh the first-mentioned interest, art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR serves as legal basis

 ** _Information obligation & rights of the data subject:_**

Facebook Ireland is obligated to novate the primary responsibility according to GDPR for the processing of Insights Data and to fulfil all duties of the GDPR in regards to the processing of Insights Data. This includes the information obligations in Articles 12 and 13 GDPR, rights of the data subject in Articles 15 to 22 GDPR and the security of the processing in Articles 32 to 34 GDPR.

 ** _Contacting_**

We forward requests regarding the rights of the data subject (art. 15 – 22 GDPR) to the primary responsible Facebook Ireland via an appropriate Facebook Page Insights Controller Form. This also includes requests for access to, the correction, the deletion and/or objections or the restriction of Insights Data as well as requests from data protection supervisory authorities relating to the processing of Insights Data within the framework of the General Data Protection Regulation.

More information about the Insights Pages regarding the person concerned can be found at: <https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/page_controller_addendum>

The data protection declaration (Facebook) can be found at: <https://www.facebook.com/privacy/>

#### Legal information

Notice to European Users: this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies.

This privacy policy relates solely to this Website.

#### Reporting Information Security Incidents

Every customer deserves to know their data is safe and secure with Productsup. Please contact us directly at [information.security@productsup.com](mailto:informationsecurity@productsup.com "mailto:informationsecurity@productsup.com") if you have any questions or concerns or if you plan to report an information security related incident.
